Contact

muhammadabuzar010@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/abuzariii (LinkedIn)

www.abuzar.social (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Web Development

Deep Learning

Business Intelligence (BI)

Certifications

Introduction to Containers w/ Docker, Kubernetes & OpenShift

Bytewise Fellowship Batch 1 (Frontend Web Development)

Bytewise Fellowship Batch 2 (Data Engineering)

Introduction to Cloud Computing Introduction to Agile Development and Scrum

Muhammad Abuzar

Self taught full-stack Web and App Developer + Deep Learning Practitioner

Bahawalpur District, Punjab, Pakistan

Summary

Experienced JavaScript Developer who can build highly responsive UIs, REST APIs, Graph QL and real time communications with Web Sockets.

I can also analyze, visualize, clean and preprocess data and then apply Machine or Deep Learning algorithms on it.

On the database side I use PostgreSQL and MongoDB as my primary databases and Power BI to make dashboards for business intelligence.

Experience

Google Developer Student Club - IUB Web Development Lead September 2023 - Present (2 months)

Bahawalpur, Punjab, Pakistan

Mentoring students across the campus to help them break into the amazing world of website development

Bytewise Limited
Data Engineering Intern
March 2023 - July 2023 (5 months)
Islāmābād. Pakistan

Learnt about creating ETL pipelines in Azure, GCP and AWS. Understood the fundamentals of cloud technology and how these platforms handle data intensive tasks.

Bytewise Limited
Frontend Intern
September 2022 - December 2022 (4 months)
Pakistan

Learned the fundamentals of modern web development including responsive web design, state management, mobile first development, routing, pagination etc

Education

The Islamia University of Bahawalpur
Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2020 - 2024)